<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Medvet</title>
    <link>https://ericmedvet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric Medvet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 17:42:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ericmedvet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphEA: a Versatile Representation and Evolutionary Algorithm for Graphs</title>
      <link>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/c-2020-mb-graphea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 17:42:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/c-2020-mb-graphea/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Many practically relevant computing artifacts are forms of graphs, as, e.g., neural networks, mathematical expressions, finite automata. This great generality of the graph abstraction makes it desirable a way for searching in the space of graphs able to work effectively regardless of the graph form and application. In this paper, we propose GraphEA, a modular evolutionary algorithm (EA) for evolving graphs. GraphEA is modular in the sense that it can be tailored to any graph optimization task by providing components for specifying how to vary edges and nodes, and how to check the validity of a graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Dimensionality Reduction Techniques for Visualizing Evolution</title>
      <link>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/c-2019-dmtb-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 16:39:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/c-2019-dmtb-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We consider the problem of visualizing the population dynamics along an evolutionary run using a dimensionality reduction technique for mapping individuals from the original search space to a 2-D space. We quantitatively assess four of these techniques in terms of their ability to preserve useful information about (a) population movements and (b) exploration-exploitation trade-off. We propose two compact visualizations aimed at highlighting these two aspects of population dynamics and evaluate them qualitatively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specializing Context-Free Grammars with a (1&#43;1)-EA</title>
      <link>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/j-2020-mbcgm-specializing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 12:30:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ericmedvet.github.io/publications/j-2020-mbcgm-specializing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Context-free grammars are useful tools for modeling the solution space of problems that can be solved by optimization algorithms. For a given solution space, there exists an infinite number of grammars defining that space, and there are clues that changing the grammar may impact the effectiveness of the optimization. In this paper, we investigate theoretically and experimentally the possibility of specializing a grammar in a problem, that is, of systematically improving the quality of the grammar for the given problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>